lifeascending.info 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from https://[www.lifeascending.info](http://lifeascending.info/)/ (the “Site”). We can be reached anytime at marianne@lifeascending.info

## Who we are

Ey to Zee is a blog about arts and crafts. Our website address is: [https://lifeascending.info](https://lifeascending.info/)

## **Your Access to and Control Over Information**

You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time.  **You can do the following at any time by contacting us via marianne@lifeascending.info:**

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

From time-to-time you may be prompted to enter your name and email address to receive free content (free online email courses, signing up for the mailing list, receiving a free download from a blog post on our site, etc.). Completing these forms is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/

## Who we share your data with

  * **PayPal:**  We accept payments through PayPal. When processing payments, some user data will be passed to PayPal, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information. Please see the PayPal Privacy Policy for more details.
  * **WooCommerce:  **WooCommerce is the eCommerce platform that we use to process orders. When you are purchasing a product, some data will be passed to WooCommerce, including information required to fulfill your order, such as your name, billing address, shipping address, product(s) purchased, the status of your transaction, your receipt, your username on our site, your email address, your IP address and the PayPal transaction associated with the purchase. Please see the WooCommerce Privacy Policy for more details.
  * **Mailchimp** : We email customers using Mailchimp. When you opt-in to our email list, your name and email address will be added to Mailchimp to be used when we send emails regarding your course and future mailing list emails. You also may also be added to our email list if you explicitly give consent while filling out a contact form, or when entering an email address in exchange for free content. Mailchimp saves information such as your email address, name, IP address, timezone, user behaviour (such as page visits and purchase activity) and certain identifying tags (such as “Blog Freebie Opt-In”) that help best tailor the appropriate emails that should or should not be sent to you, a list of which emails were sent and the actions that you took on those emails (for example, opened, clicked on a link, etc.). You can unsubscribe to these emails at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found in these emails or by emailing your request to marianne@lifeascending.info. Please see the Mailchimp Privacy Policy for more details.

Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you have signed up to receive email communications through us, we retain your email address and name until we receive a request from you to delete this data. You may do so at any time by contacting us at marianne@lifeascending.info.

If you have purchased a product or products through us, we retain your order information until we receive a request from you to delete this data. You may do so at any time by contacting us at marianne@lifeascending.info.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## AFFILIATE LINKS

Some blog posts and web pages within this site contain affiliate links.

An affiliate link is used as a mechanism for revenue generation. This revenue is generated by users who click on ads or hyperlinks within this website and then subsequently make a purchase on a third party website.

While the link usage does not increase a visitor’s purchase price, usage of the link may result in a commission that is credited to this website.

We have chosen to recommend products and services that we personally use or have thoroughly researched.

The opinions expressed here are not necessarily the opinions of nor reflect the views of any merchants we are affiliated with or represent via affiliate links.

## ACCEPTANCE OF THESE TERMS

By using this website, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our website.

### **YOUR PRIVACY IS IMPORTANT TO US AND WE CAN BE CONTACTED ANYTIME AT MARIANNE@LIFEASCENDING.INFO WITH ANY CONCERNS YOU MAY HAVE.**
